Guide to the American Institute of Planners Records, 1934-1978
American Institute of Planners Records, 1934-1978
- Series I. General AIP Files
  - Education - Robert L. Williams, 1965-1968 (Box 74, Folder 31)
  - Burke Peterson file, 1965-1966 (Box 74, Folder 32)
  - Burke Peterson file, 1963-1967 (Box 74, Folder 33)
  - Reference material - position statement, 1958-1961 (Box 74, Folder 34)
  - Role of planning in area redevelopment, 1963 (Box 74, Folder 35)
  - University of North Carolina - role of planning study, 1958-1960 (Box 74, Folder 36)
  - "Role and Scope" of planning, 1959 (Box 74, Folder 37)
  - Association of Collegiate Schools of Planning (ACSP), 1970-1971 (Box 74, Folder 38)
  - ACSP (general - including Philadelphia and Portland meetings), 1966 (Box 74, Folder 39)
  - ACSP (general), 1959-1963 (Box 74, Folder 40)
  - ACSP (general), 1964 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - ACSP (general), 1965 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - ACSP origins, 1958 (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Planning school recognition - National Membership Committee, 1958-1970 (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - Recognition of planning schools - Ad hoc Inter-Divisional Committee, 1963-1969 (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - Program for planning students - student awards program, 1960-1964 (Box 75, Folder 6)
  - Division of Planning Education - CALC (California Chapter) planning education, 1958-1961 (Box 75, Folder 7)
  - Division of Planning Education - sub-professional education, 1966 (Box 75, Folder 8)
  - Division of Planning Education - training programs - HUD (Division of International Affairs), 1966 (Box 75, Folder 9)
  - Division of Planning Education - reconstruction training - George Nez proposal, 1965-1966 (Box 75, Folder 10)
  - Division of Planning Education - Meltzer proposal for planning education study, 1962-1964 (Box 75, Folder 11)
  - Division of Planning Education - manpower - May/Hamilton paper at Government Relations and Planning Policy Conference, 1965 (Box 75, Folder 12)
  - Committee on Continuing Education - Toronto, 1965 (Box 75, Folder 13)
  - Continuing Education - portion of 1965 AIP membership survey, 1965-1966 (Box 75, Folder 14)
  - Committee on Continuing Education - St. Louis, 1965 (Box 75, Folder 15)
  - Philadelphia Regional Chapter (PHRC) - Education Committee/Byer, 1964-1966 (Box 75, Folder 16)
  - New England Chapter, Boston Section - Continuing Education (Box 75, Folder 17)
  - Committee on Continuing Education (Dolbeare), 1954-1966 (Box 75, Folder 18)
  - Continuing Education - International City Managers' Association project (Box 75, Folder 19)
  - Vocational guidance brochure and publication, 1965-1966 (Box 75, Folder 20)
  - AIP/ASPO/ACSP Joint Committee, 1966 (Box 75, Folder 21)
  - AIP/ASPO Education Committee - Toronto, 1965 (Box 75, Folder 22)
  - AIP/ASPO Joint Committee on Education (Box 75, Folder 23-25)
  - HUD Fellowship Program (Box 75, Folder 26)
  - HUD Urban Studies Advisory Board Meeting, 1967 (Box 75, Folder 27)
  - S. 593 (to amend Title VIII) - Ribicoff, 1967 (Box 75, Folder 28)
  - Title IX (Demonstration Cities and Metropolitan Development Act), 1966 (Box 75, Folder 29)
  - Rep. Alexander Pirnie - Planning Education (Box 75, Folder 30)
  - Title VIII - Historical (through 1965) - testimony, etc. on both authorization and appropriations (Box 75, Folder 31-33)
  - Title VIII - Part I (Federal/state training) program guides, releases, etc. (Box 75, Folder 34)
  - Fellowship programs - Bureau of the Budget, Dave Wilcox - Bob Aten study, 1968 (Box 75, Folder 35)
  - Title VIII - fellowships, 1968 (Box 75, Folder 36)
  - Title VIII - interim file (Box 75, Folder 37-38)
  - State Department of Urban Affairs (Box 75, Folder 39)
  - The Benefits and Costs of Alternative Federal Programs of Financial Aid to College Students - Andre Daniere, Ph.D., 1969 (Box 75, Folder 40)
  - Aids to planning education (publication project) (Box 75, Folder 41)
  - Loula D. Lasker Fellowship Trust - announcements (Box 75, Folder 42)
  - Action, Pittsburgh Plate Glass Foundation (PPGF) project (Box 75, Folder 43)
  - PPGF - planning (and other) fellowships (Box 75, Folder 44)
  - Richard King Mellon Charitable Trusts - graduate planning fellowships (Box 75, Folder 45)
  - Stern Family Fund (Box 75, Folder 46)
  - Sears, United Student Aid Funds, Inc. - loan guarantee program (Box 75, Folder 47)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 75, Folder 48)
  - Sears-Roebuck Foundation - graduate city planning fellowships (Box 75, Folder 49)
  - Urban design fellowships (Box 75, Folder 50)
  - Sears-Roebuck Foundation - planning faculty internship program (Box 75, Folder 51)
  - Higher education - S. 600, Title I, 1965-1968 (Box 75, Folder 52)
  - Stipend program, 1965-1968 (Box 75, Folder 53)
  - Stipend program, 1965-1970 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - National Arts Council travel grants (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - United Student Aid Funds (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - 50th anniversary - "The Next 50 Years: 1967-2017", 1966-1969 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - 50th anniversary - Washington, D.C. (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Welcoming address - Urban Planning Commemorative Stamp Ceremony - host, AIP: press conference, 1967 (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - "The Next Fifty Years" - syllabus, videocassette transcripts, Part I: Perspectives: Group A: Creating the Future Environment (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Videocassette transcripts - Part I: Perspectives; Group B: Technology, Society, and the Individual, 1973 (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Videocassette transcripts - Part II: Priorities; Group C: The Urgent and the Important, 1973 (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - Videocassette transcripts - Part II: Priorities; Group D: The Nation and the World (Box 76, Folder 10)
  - AIP corporate bylaws adopted April 5, 1970 as amended to June 21, 1972, February 25, 1973, and May 12, 1974, 1970-1974 (Box 76, Folder 11)
  - Task Force Book on Program and Budget, 1968 (Box 76, Folder 12)
  - "A Manual for Conducting the AIP Membership Oral Examination", 1969 (Box 76, Folder 13)
  - Brochure for Planning and the New Federalism: 56th Annual Conference of the American Institute of Planners - Atlanta, Georgia, October 21-25, 1973 (Box 84)
  - The Ladislas Segoe Tapes Transcript - Recorded in Cincinnati, Ohio - Syndey H. Williams (Tapes 1-3), May 22-24, 1978 (Box 84)
- Series II. ASPO-Ford Foundation Fellowship Program
  - Ford Foundation Minority Fellowship Program, 1974 (Box 76, Folder 14)
  - University of Iowa, 1974-1976 (Box 76, Folder 15)
  - Columbia University, 1973-1975 (Box 76, Folder 16)
  - Cornell University, 1973-1975 (Box 76, Folder 17)
  - Georgia Institute of Technology, 1973-1975 (Box 76, Folder 18)
  - Harvard University, 1973-1975 (Box 76, Folder 19)
  - University of Iowa, 1973-1975 (Box 76, Folder 20)
  - Kansas State University, 1973-1974 (Box 76, Folder 21)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1973-1975 (Box 76, Folder 22)
  - Program working file, 1974 (Box 76, Folder 23-24)
  - University of Arizona, 1974-1976 (Box 76, Folder 25)
  - California State University - San Jose, 1974-1976 (Box 76, Folder 26)
  - UCLA - Los Angeles, 1974-1976 (Box 76, Folder 27)
  - University of Cincinnati, 1974-1976 (Box 76, Folder 28)
  - Cornell University, 1974-1976 (Box 76, Folder 29)
  - Fisk University, 1974-1976 (Box 76, Folder 30)
  - Howard University, 1974-1976 (Box 76, Folder 31-32)
  - University of Oklahoma, 1973-1975 (Box 76, Folder 33)
  - University of Cincinnati, 1971-1973 (Box 76, Folder 34-35)
  - University of California - Berkeley, 1972-1974 (Box 76, Folder 36)
  - Pepperdine University, 1973-1975 (Box 76, Folder 37)
  - University of Tennessee, 1973-1975 (Box 76, Folder 38)
  - Southern Illinois University, 1973-1975 (Box 76, Folder 39)
  - University of Rhode Island, 1973-1974 (Box 76, Folder 40)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1974-1976 (Box 76, Folder 41)
  - Morgan State College, 1974-1976 (Box 76, Folder 42)
  - Pepperdine University, 1974-1976 (Box 76, Folder 43)
  - University of Pittsburgh, 1974-1976 (Box 76, Folder 44)
  - University of Pittsburgh, 1973-1975 (Box 76, Folder 45)
  - California Polytechnic University, 1973-1975 (Box 76, Folder 46)
  - California State University - San Jose, 1973-1975 (Box 76, Folder 47)
  - University of Arizona, 1973-1975 (Box 76, Folder 48)
  - University of Washington, 1974-1976 (Box 76, Folder 49)
  - University of Cincinnati, 1973-1975 (Box 76, Folder 50)
  - Clemson University, 1973-1975 (Box 76, Folder 51)
  - Cornell University, 1971-1973 (Box 76, Folder 52)
  - Florida State University, 1971-1973 (Box 76, Folder 53)
  - Hunter College, 1971-1973 (Box 76, Folder 54)
  - University of Illinois, 1971-1973 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - New York University, 1971-1973 (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - University of Tennessee, 1971-1973 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute, 1971-1973 (Box 77, Folder 4-5)
  - University of Washington, 1970-1972 (Box 77, Folder 6-7)
  - University of Oklahoma, 1970-1972 (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - University of California - Los Angeles, 1972-1974 (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - Cornell University, 1972-1974 (Box 77, Folder 10)
  - George Washington University, 1972-1974 (Box 77, Folder 11)
  - Kansas State University, 1972-1974 (Box 77, Folder 12)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1972-1974 (Box 77, Folder 13)
  - Michigan State University, 1972-1974 (Box 77, Folder 14)
  - New York University, 1972-1974 (Box 77, Folder 15)
  - University of Oklahoma, 1972-1974 (Box 77, Folder 16)
  - University of Virginia, 1970-1972 (Box 77, Folder 17)
  - University of Rhode Island, 1970-1972 (Box 77, Folder 18)
  - University of Rhode Island, 1971-1973 (Box 77, Folder 19)
  - University of Oklahoma, 1971-1973 (Box 77, Folder 20)
  - University of Pittsburgh, 1972-1974 (Box 77, Folder 21)
  - Grantees, 1971-1973 (Box 77, Folder 22)
  - New York University, 1970-1972 (Box 77, Folder 23)
  - Rutgers University, 1970-1972 (Box 77, Folder 24-25)
  - University of Michigan, 1970-1972 (Box 77, Folder 26)
  - Grantees, 1970-1971 (Box 77, Folder 27)
  - University of Washington, 1972-1974 (Box 77, Folder 28)
  - University of California - Berkeley, 1970-1972 (Box 77, Folder 29)
  - University of Washington, 1970-1972 (Box 77, Folder 30)
  - ASPO proposals, 1974-1976 (Box 77, Folder 31-38)
  - Kansas State Materials (Box 77, Folder 39)
  - "A Proposal for the Funding of Fellowships in the ASPO-Ford Program for Minority Students in Graduate Planning Programs" submitted by University of Cincinnati, 1971-1972 (Box 77, Folder 40)
  - "Proposal to the ASPO-Ford Foundation Minority Fellowship Program in Planning for" by Graduate Planning Program, Georgia Institute of Technology, 1974-1976 (Box 77, Folder 41)
  - "Proposal to the ASPO-Ford Foundation Minority Fellowship Program in Planning for 1974-1976" - correspondence (Box 77, Folder 42)
  - Proposals for ASPO-Ford Foundation Fellowship Program, 1970 (Box 77, Folder 43-44)
  - Program working file, 1973 (Box 77, Folder 45)
  - Ford Foundation official correspondence, 1973 (Box 77, Folder 46)
  - Program working file, 1972 (Box 77, Folder 47)
  - Program working file, 1971 (Box 77, Folder 48)
  - Program working file, 1970 (Box 77, Folder 49)
  - Program working file (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - ASPO-Ford fellows - summer internships (Box 78, Folder 2-3)
  - School Selection Committee correspondence, 1973 (Box 78, Folder 4-5)
  - School Selection Committee correspondence, 1971 (Box 78, Folder 6-7)
  - School Selection Committee correspondence, 1970 (Box 78, Folder 8-9)
  - Ford Foundation official correspondence, 1972 (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - School Selection Committee correspondence, 1972 (Box 78, Folder 11-12)
  - "A Proposal to Use Ford Foundation Fellowship Funds in Planning for Black Americans from Graduate Department of Planning, University of Cincinnati", 1970-1971 (Box 78, Folder 13)
  - "A Proposal to Use Ford Foundation Fellowship Funds in Planning for Black Americans from Graduate Department of Planning, University of Cincinnati" - Exhibit 10 (Box 78, Folder 14)
  - ASPO-Ford Foundation Program - proposals for awards (A-C) (Box 78, Folder 15)
  - ASPO-Ford Foundation Program - proposals for awards (F-I) (Box 78, Folder 16)
  - ASPO-Ford Foundation Program - proposals for awards (K-P) (Box 78, Folder 17)
  - ASPO-Ford Foundation Program - proposals for awards (R-W) (Box 78, Folder 18)
  - Ford Foundation grant #3 - School Selection Committee minutes (Box 78, Folder 19-20)
  - Ford Foundation grant #3 - school correspondence (Box 78, Folder 21)
  - Ford Foundation grant #3 - school checks (Box 78, Folder 22-23)
  - Ford Foundation grant #3 - miscellaneous (Box 78, Folder 24)
  - Ford Foundation grant #3 - general correspondence (Box 78, Folder 25-26)
  - ASPO proposals, 1971 (Box 78, Folder 27)
  - ASPO proposals, 1970-1971 (Box 78, Folder 28-29)
  - Ford Foundation grant #3 - basic documents (Box 78, Folder 30-32)
  - ASPO proposals, 1970-1971 (Box 78, Folder 33-34)
  - ASPO proposals, 1971 (Box 78, Folder 35)
  - "Proposal for UMTS-URT Grant for" - Virginia Polytechnic Institute, 1971-1974 (Box 78, Folder 36)
  - ASPO proposals, 1971 (Box 78, Folder 37)
  - ASPO proposals, 1971-1972 (Box 78, Folder 38-39)
  - ASPO proposals, 1973 (Box 78, Folder 40-41)
  - ASPO proposals, 1973 (Box 78, Folder 42)
- Series III. Applications from universities with planning programs for AIP recognition
  - Hunter College (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Master of Science (Planning) (Box 79, Folder 2-3)
  - University of Cincinnati, 1969 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Columbia University, 1969 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - California Polytechnic State University, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - Pennsylvania State University, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Princeton University, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - California Polytechnic State University, 1974 (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - Morgan State College, 1974 (Box 79, Folder 10)
  - Wayne State University, 1975 (Box 79, Folder 11)
  - University of Maryland, 1976 (Box 79, Folder 12-13)
  - University of British Columbia, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 14)
  - University of California, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 15)
  - University of Cincinnati, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 16-17)
  - Columbia University, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 18)
  - Cornell University, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 19)
  - George Washington University, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 20)
  - Georgia Institute of Technology, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 21)
  - Michigan State University, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 22)
  - University of Montreal, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 23)
  - University of Oklahoma, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 24)
  - University of Oregon, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 25)
  - University of Puerto Rico, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 26)
  - Rutgers University, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 27)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 28)
  - University of Washington, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 29)
- Series IV. Publications
  - 1. "Scope and Point of View of AIP's 50th Year Conference" (Box 80)
  - 2. Poster size - schedule of events, Part II, Washington Conference (Box 80)
  - 3. AIP's Special 50th Anniversary Awards (Box 80)
  - 4. "Planning and the Planning Profession" by Russel Van Nest Black, AIP (Box 80)
  - 5. "Bibliography Studies of Future Technology, Change and Philosophies of Life" by William R. Ewald, Jr. (Box 80)
  - 6. One book mark (Box 80)
  - 7. Thursday's program and "Who's Who" (4 copies) (Box 80)
  - AIP 1967: Commemorative Program proposals (Box 80)
  - Supplement to bibliography (no. 5 above) (Box 80)
  - Supplementary projections for, 1965-2020 (Box 80)
  - Miscellany including videocassette labels, questionnaires, conference registration, information, future conference perspectives (in July 1968); program event schedules (August 1966), 1966, 1968 (Box 80)
  - Status of AIP's 50th year consultation (Box 80)
  - Background for all conference participants (Box 80)
  - Purpose and Philosophy - the Next 50 Years (Box 80)
  - Summary of partial list of commissioned papers (Box 80)
  - Conference of 2020 (Box 80)
  - Letter to Harland Bartholomew, chairman of 50th Anniversary committee (Box 80)
  - William R. Ewald, Jr. correspondence, 1961-1965 (Box 80)
  - William R. Ewald, Jr., notes and correspondence regarding publications from AIP's 1967 50th Year conference (Box 80)
  - Miscellaneous AIP publications, 1958-1975 (Box 81)
  - Miscellaneous AIP publications, 1958-1975 (Box 82)
  - Miscellaneous AIP publications, 1958-1975 (Box 83)
- Series V. Films
  - “Blueprint for Progress,” Industrial Sound Films, Inc., Atlanta, Ga., ca. 1959; F-1620
  - Untitled, ca. 1979; F-1621
  - Untitled, ca. 1979; F-1622